Xavier University Department of Physics records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Department of Physics records
1946-1987
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Department of Physics
1 linear feet (2 boxes)
This is a small collection of documents generated by or associated with the Physics Department at Xavier University.
XUA-66
Scope and Content
This small collection of documents includes Physics Department minutes, correspondence and reports. Other documents cover various persons or activities stemming from or associated with the Physics Department.
Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports
Programs and Activities
Faculty Biographical Information
Papers, Proposals,and Photographs
Statement of Arrangement
Materials are arranged into folders by general series.
Separated Material
Photographs originally found with this collection have been digitized and are now found in a separate photograph collection. Photographs and corresponding scanned image numbers are 12820 to 12870.
Restrictions on Access
Some materials may have restricted access. Please contact the archives staff.
Accruals
Additions to this collection are expected.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Physics--Study and teaching
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports, 1946-1987
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Reports, 1946; 1954-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Reports, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Reports, 1964-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Reports, 1977-1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Programs and Activities, 1956-1962
  - Operation Deep Freeze, Antarctica, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Operation Deep Freeze, Antarctica, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Operation Deep Freeze, Antarctica, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Operation Deep Freeze, Antarctica, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Quantum Electronics Symposium, 1961 September 20 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Conference on Foundations of Quantum Mechanics, 1962; undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Faculty Biographical Information, 1960-1969
  - Teachers of Physics, 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Papers, Proposals, and Photographs, 1966-1987
  - Ultimate Temperatures: Ramque's Vortex Tube (Fulton), 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Physics Laboratories Photos, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Tools for Discovery: Exploring Nature with Microcomputer-based Lab Instruments (Yerian), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)